Profile

I am a Recent Cybersecurity Graduate from Edith Cowan University with a varied and multidisciplinary background: a Masters degree in Political Economy from Sydney University, a Master's degree in Strategic Studies from the Australian National University, an Honours graduate in Science from James Cook University with majors in zoology and microbiology, a certificate III in information technology and a Cambridge CELTA. I am also proficient in French (level B2), along with basic Arabic, Spanish, and German. I have experience in traveling and working in developing countries including Africa, and experience working for international organisations such as the World Health Organization, as well as working as a polling assistant during the 2016 Australian Federal election and the 2017 NSW local elections.

Personal

Address: Apartment 1/1A Ocean Street Kogarah

Citizenship: Dual Australian, Irish

Languages Spoken: English (mother tongue), French (intermediate), basic Spanish, Arabic and

German

Education

Feb 2019 – Present Graduate Diploma in Cybersecurity

Current postgraduate student of cybersecurity at Edith Cowan university, expecting to complete a graduate diploma by the end of the year, delayed due to Covid-19.

Jan 2015 – 2017 Master of Political Economy

This degree involves the study of economics as it can be applied to a variety of policy situations in order to produce a desired outcome. As part of this degree I completed a dissertation entitled 'Market Structure and pharmaceutical pricing", which examined the economic causes behind the current high prices of medicines.

Dissertation Supervisor – Dr Tim Anderson

Feb 2014 - Mar 2014 Cambridge Certificate of English Language Teaching to Adults (CELTA)

The qualification involved training in the teaching of English to speakers of other languages using the Cambridge CELTA methodology

Jan 2013 – Jul 2013 Certificate III in information, digital media and technology from the Canberra Institute of Technology

The qualification involved training in system administration, information technology, building and servicing computers and basic network structures

Jan 2012 – Dec 2012. Master of strategic studies, graduated with merit. The Australian National University.

The degree included subjects on security, government, and strategy in the Asia-Pacific region, the strategic and defence challenges of China, insurgency, and counterinsurgency in the modern world, as well as grand strategy in the Asia-Pacific.

2007 – 2010, Bachelor of Science with Honours (IIA), majoring in zoology and microbiology, James Cook University.

Thesis Title: The development, validation and application of in-situ hybridisation as a tool for the study of Fibropapilloma Associated Turtle Herpesvirus. During the three-year coursework section of the degree I Studied subjects that included statistics, Immunology, Food Microbiology, marine microbiology, ecology and epidemiology.

Supervisors: Dr. Ellen Ariel, Assc. Prof. Leigh Owens

Experience

Aug 2018- Present Operating my own indie computer games studio, Future Indie Darlings, publishing games on Android

Sep 2017 Worked as a polling assistant for the council election at the Allawah senior citizens centre polling place. This involved assisting people with their ballots as well as doing the final count for the polling place once voting had finished.

Jul 2016 Worked as a polling assistant for the federal election at the south Coogee polling place. This involved assisting people with their ballots as well as doing the final count for the polling place once voting had finished.

Jul 2014 – Oct 2014 Completed an internship at the World Health Organization (WHO) Headquarters in Geneva, working with the Secretariat for the International Health Regulations (2005). The internship involved supporting the secretariat with preparation work for the International Health Regulations 2014 Review Committee and the Ebola Virus Disease Emergency Committee.

Apr 2011 - Jun 2011 Completed an industrial attachment at Kenya Institute of Medical Research in Nairobi, Kenya, involving the use of numerous laboratory techniques to study a series of tropical diseases, including malaria, HIV, and schistosomiasis.

Nov 2008 – Dec 2009 Tropical zoology fieldwork in Borneo and North Queensland including bat handling and speciation, and the capture, tag and release of marine turtles. I am fully immunised against most tropical diseases, including rabies and yellow fever.

Published Computer Games

Seagull! - Arcade style Game available on the Google Play Store under the Future Indie Darlings Brand

Reef Rush - Arcade game for the Android platform available on the Google Play Store under the Future Indie Darlings Brand

Teaching

Preparation and delivery of lectures for undergraduate students at James Cook University,

English as a second language classes to adults at Holmesglen as part of the Cambridge CELTA.

Tutoring biology for high school students (2013)

Research

Research assistant on universal healthcare report for AIHSS on healthcare in Indonesia.

Key Skills

Independent research and analysis in science and political science/strategic studies

Proficient in writing technical documents for public health, scientific, social science and strategic areas

Proficient in scientific and political science writing, scientific field and laboratory skills

High level of proficiency with word processing, presentation, and spreadsheet software including Microsoft office suite, as well as experience with SQL, Javascript, C#, Unity and Blender, experience with Kali Linux, Wireshark and Cisco Packet Tracer.

Fluent with both Macintosh and Windows operating systems

Proficient in French, basic German and basic Arabic (completed a number of introductory and continuing Arabic courses at Since 2011)

Scientific and Laboratory skills

Laboratory skills (PC2) experience, including PCR, in-situ hybridisation and general laboratory microbiology skills including light, phase contrast, interference microscopy, plating, cell counting, slide preparation, cell culture, use of a fluorescence activated cell sorter.

Interests

Wide-ranging interests in history and politics

War-gaming (computer and model), miniature model making

Game development

Advanced downhill skier

Cooking

SCUBA diving

References

Personal References

Dr. Faith Mclellan

E-Mail: faithmclellan@gmail.com

Dr. Charles Penn

E-Mail: charlesrpenn@gmail.com

Professional References

Dr. Adrienne Rashford

Email: rashforda@who.int

Phone 41227911562

Dr. Ellen Ariel: Ph: (07) 47814123

E-Mail: ellen.ariel@jcu.edu.au

Assc. Prof. Dr. Leigh Owens: Ph: (07) 47814632

E-Mail: leigh.owens@jcu.edu.au

Dr. Rashid J.R., Chief Research Officer, Centre for Clinical Research, Kenya Medical Research Institute

Ph: 254 - 020 - 2726781

E-Mail: Jrashid@kemri.org